Taha YASSINE

Taha YASSINE | in Taha YASSINE | \oplus tahayassine.me | \boxtimes taha.yssne@gmail.com | \blacksquare +33 6 21 83 58 65

SUMMARY

I received the engineering degree in computer science from the National Institute of Applied Sciences (INSA Rennes, France), and the M.Sc. degree in reseach in computer science from the University of Rennes 1 (Rennes, France), in 2020. I am currently pursuing the Ph.D. degree with INSA Rennes, IETR (Rennes, France) and b<>com (Rennes, France). My current research topics include signal processing, wireless communications and machine learning. Additionally, I have interest in broader AI topics such as computer vision and NLP.

Work Experience

PhD student (b<>com)

Oct. 2020 - present

Propose and develop deep learning models for different physical level tasks (channel estimation, beamforming, channel charting...) in the context of massive MIMO systems. The models are inspired and guided by principles derived from signal processing and wireless communications theory. Produce papers presenting the work.

Research internship (b<>com)

Feb. 2020 - July 2020

Developped a deep learning model for channel estimation in the context of massive MIMO systems. The internship was a great introduction to doing research and an opportunity to get a foot in the door. Produced a paper presenting the work as well.

EDUCATION

2020 - present PhD in wireless communications and machine learning with INSA Rennes, IETR and

b<>com

2019 Erasmus exchange at Newcastle University

2015 - 2020 Engineering degree in computer science at **INSA Rennes**

Publications

Luc Le Magoarou, **Taha Yassine**, Stéphane Paquelet, and Matthieu Crussière (Oct. 2022). "Channel charting based beamforming". In: 2022 56th Asilomar Conference on Signals, Systems, and Computers. Pacific Grove, CA, USA. Pacific Grove, CA, USA: IEEE, pp. 1185–1189. ISBN: 978-1-6654-5907-5. DOI: 10.1109/IEEECONF56349.2022.10051826.

Luc Le Magoarou, **Taha Yassine**, Stéphane Paquelet, and Matthieu Crussière (May 2022). "Deep Learning for Location Based Beamforming with Nlos Channels". In: *ICASSP 2022 - 2022 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP)*. Singapore, Singapore, Singapore: IEEE, pp. 8812–8816. ISBN: 978-1-6654-0541-6. DOI: 10.1109/ICASSP43922.2022.9747293.

Taha Yassine and Luc Le Magoarou (July 2022). "mpNet: Variable Depth Unfolded Neural Network for Massive MIMO Channel Estimation". In: *IEEE Transactions on Wireless Communications* 21.7 (99), pp. 5703–5714. ISSN: 1558-2248. DOI: 10.1109/TWC.2022.3142737.

Taha Yassine, Luc Le Magoarou, Stéphane Paquelet, and Matthieu Crussière (July 2022). "Leveraging triplet loss and nonlinear dimensionality reduction for on-the-fly channel charting". In: 2022 IEEE 23rd International Workshop on Signal Processing Advances in Wireless Communication (SPAWC). Oulu,

Finland. Oulu, Finland: IEEE, pp. 1–5. ISBN: 978-1-6654-9456-4. DOI: 10.1109/SPAWC51304.2022.9834035.

Mattia Merluzzi et al. (2023). "The Hexa-X Project Vision on Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning-Driven Communication and Computation Co-Design for 6G". In: *IEEE Access* 11, pp. 65620–65648. ISSN: 2169-3536. DOI: 10.1109/ACCESS.2023.3287939.

Taha Yassine, Luc Le Magoarou, Baptiste Chatelier, et al. (Aug. 2023). "Cartographie du canal par réduction de dimension et réseaux triplets". In: 29° Colloque sur le traitement du signal et des images. 2023-1381. Grenoble: GRETSI - Groupe de Recherche en Traitement du Signal et des Images, pp. 1165–1168.

SKILLS

Programming Python, Java, C/C++, Bash.

Frameworks/Libraries PyTorch, NumPy, scikit-learn, SciPy, Sionna, Matplotlib, Bokeh.

Other Docker.

Last updated: September 15, 2023